I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
（隊員）人形を発見！
Doll secured!
Ariel!
（小隊長）これは…。→
This is...
Ariel!
野戦指揮所に報告！
問題の樽を発見した！
Report back to Field Ops Command.
We found the barrel!
（隊員）樽を発見した！
Episode 20
Whodunit (Who did it?)
（早河）そうか　ほぼ無傷なんだな。
I see, so there's very little damage?
では　最優先で搬送してくれ。
Then send it over immediately.
（山本）これも　姫様の言うところの
理のなせる業かしら。
I wonder if this is the princess affecting logic again.
しかし　とんでもないことを
思いつくものだ。
She certainly came up with a ridiculous plan.
再び　時間を飛び越えるとは…。
To think she would want to travel through time again...
（葉風・回想）
((私は再び　過去に戻り→
I plan to travel back in time,
before Fuwa Aika's murder, to witness it myself.
起こるであろう
不破愛花殺人事件の目撃者となる))
Back in time?
Last time, I used my skeleton as a focal point
（葉風）((かつて　私は
私自身の全身骨格を焦点にして→
and transferred my flesh onto it, as a means of moving from past to present.
肉を移し替えることで
過去から現在へと戻ってきた))
（葉風）
((島にある全身骨格のそばには→
The doll and barrel should be next to the skeleton.
人形と樽が
そのままになっていよう。→
人形には
私の血が染み込ませてあり→
The doll has been soaked in my blood. The barrel,
樽には　左門
貴様の血が染み込ませてあるな？))
Samon, has absorbed yours.
Yes.
（左門）((はい。　万が一のとき
通信具となるよう　板の一部に))
In the event we required a means of communication,
I soaked one board.
((この人形と樽　二つともあれば
過去ともつながりやすい))
As long as we have this doll and barrel,
connecting to the past should be easy.
((更に
骨を使って位置を特定すれば→
If I use the skeleton to triangulate the location,
私が骨になってから
左門が回収するまでの→
I should be able to travel sometime between when I turned into a skeleton
どこかの時間へ行けるはずだ。→
and when Samon retrieved me.
そして　運よく
不破愛花が殺害されたとされる→
Then, if I'm lucky, I can reach the Fuwa mansion before the time of Fuwa Aika's murder
この時刻より前に
不破の屋敷にたどりつければ→
and discover with my own eyes by whom, how, and why
誰が　どうやって　なんのために
殺人を行ったか…))
she was killed.
((この目で見ることができる。→
真広　吉野→
Mahiro.
Yoshino.
不破愛花を誰が殺したのか…。→
The person who killed Fuwa Aika...
はじまりの樹が
なんらかの意図を持って→
It's possible the Tree of Genesis may have been behind it,
仕組んだのかもしれん。
あるいは　絶園の魔法使いが→
or perhaps, the mage of Exodus was somehow responsible.
なんらかの謀略を
持っていたのかもしれん))
However,
((しかし…→
どんな真相であれ
必ず　お前たちに伝える。→
whatever the truth may be,
I promise to bring it to you.
I will tell you every last bit of the truth,
すべて残らず　真実を語る))
and then my promise will be fulfilled.
((これで約束を果たせる))
（潤一郎）((でも
葉風ちゃんが　計画どおりに→
But...
Supposing you can reach the crime scene in time as you intend to,
殺人の現場に
居合わせられるのなら→
なぜ
事件を止められなかったのか))
why couldn't you prevent it from happening?
((止められないにしても→
And if you can't prevent it,
why couldn't you still save her with magic?
なぜ　愛花さんを
魔法で助けられなかったのか))
Wouldn't it change history if she did that?
((それをやっちゃうと
過去の改変になるんじゃないの？))
Exactly. That's also why I think
（潤一郎）((そう
だからこそ　葉風ちゃんは→
that Hakaze cannot go precisely where she wants to in the past.
望んだ過去へは行けない
とも考えられる))
（葉風）((確かに　そうだな。
現在　出ている結果は変えられん))
That's true.
I cannot change the present reality.
（羽村）
((それじゃ　過去へ行く意味が…))
But then there's no point in going—
There is.
（葉風）((いや　たとえ不破愛花を
助けられないとしても→
Even if I cannot save Fuwa Aika,
I should be able to learn her killer's identity.
犯人の正体を
知ることはできるであろう。→
それなら　現在と矛盾せず
目的を果たすことができる。→
That way, I can still complete my task without interfering with the present.
どうする？　真広))
How about it, Mahiro?
（不破真広）
((リスクを負うのは　お前だ))
You're the one putting yourself at risk.
((そのお前がやる気なら
反対する理由はねぇよ))
If you're okay with it, I have no reason to object.
At this point, there's probably no other way to find the murderer.
((もう
犯人が分かりそうにないのも→
確かだからな))
((よし。→
All right.
If there are no other objections,
これ以上の
反対意見がなければ…))
（葉風）((各自
私の指示どおりに動いてくれ))
all of you, please do as I say!
So the requirements are the doll, the barrel, and...
そのために必要なものが
人形　樽　そして…。
We'll leave acquiring the offering to you.
残る供物の方　よろしくね。
手配はしてある。→
I've already secured it.
空対空ミサイル１発程度なら
お安いものだ。
One air-to-air missile wasn't a problem at all.
なんだ？
よかったわね　中央に返り咲けて。
What?
Congratulations on your return to Central.
バカ言え。
やることが増えただけだ。
Save it.
It just means I have more to do now.
（葉風）あの島の正確な位置と
隠された供物のありか→
The location of that island, as well as the location of the offering,
それで間違いないな？
はい。
are as indicated, correct?
Yes.
But...
（葉風）しかし…。
しかし？
But?
（葉風）初めて　マッサージ機
というものを使ってみたが→
This is my first time using a massage chair,
but it just tickles.
くすぐったいだけだな。
そもそも　肩が凝るというのも
どういう状態か分からん。
Then again, I don't really know how stiff shoulders feel.
（左門）この世の理から
加護を受ける姫様が→
If the princess who is protected by the world's logic were to get stiff shoulders, that would indeed be
肩凝りを起こすようでは
世も末でしょう。
the end of the world.
（葉風）とはいえ　貴様も　その年で
白髪もなく長髪でいられるのだ。→
Not to mention,
you've managed to keep your long hair without a single gray strand at your age.
言うほど　苦労性ではあるまい。
I doubt you're as troubled as you'd suggest.
（左門）いえ　実は　これは→
No, actually,
カツラなのです。
this is a wig.
えっ!?
うそ!?
What?
You're kidding!
（左門）はい　うそです。
Indeed, I am.
（葉風）貴様が　そんな冗談を
言うヤツとは思わなかったぞ。
I never took you for the type to joke.
When you're troubled as long as I have been, you start wanting to make a joke or two.
苦労が続けば
冗談も言いたくなります。
それより　姫様。
More importantly, Princess,
what is your real reason for traveling to the past?
過去に飛ばれる本当の目的は
なんなのです？
I already told you,
言ったであろう　不破愛花殺人犯を
突き止めるためだと。
to track down Fuwa Aika's murderer.
That may very well be what you intend to do,
そのつもりでは
あられるでしょうが→
but I cannot dismiss the possibility
場合によっては　その手で直接→
不破愛花を
殺すおつもりではないかと。
that you might try to kill Fuwa Aika.
（葉風）かつて　不破愛花殺人犯を
魔法で探査した際→
When we previously investigated the identity of Fuwa Aika's killer,
no one was caught by the web of magic.
何者も
その網にかからなかった。→
だが　探査をした時点では
殺人を犯していない→
However, if the culprit is ultimately my future self
who had yet to commit the murder at the time of the investigation,
未来の私が犯人なら
矛盾が解消され　辻褄が合う。
then the inconsistencies are explained, and it all makes sense.
（潤一郎）それ
因果関係　おかしくないかい？
Does that chain of cause and effect even make sense?
（葉風）時間を越えるのだ。→
I'm going back in time.
そんな因果があっても
よいではないか。
I don't find it too unreasonable.
それに　いちばん怖いのはな→
Besides, what I fear most
is that the truth will actually be rather dull.
真実がつまらないことなのだよ。
つまらない？
Dull?
Someone meaningless killed Fuwa Aika meaninglessly
不破愛花は　つまらない人間に
つまらない理由で殺され→
そのつまらない犯人も
この世界の混乱の中→
for some meaningless purpose,
and that meaningless suspect
すでに　つまらなく死んでいる。→
has already died meaninglessly amidst the current chaos.
If this were the truth to be revealed,
そんな真実が明らかになれば
吉野や真広は　どうなる？→
what of Mahiro and Yoshino?
不破愛花の死には
なんの意味もない。
Fuwa Aika's death would be meaningless.
She'd have died meaninglessly,
彼女は　つまらなく死に→
and there could be no revenge.
復讐の物語を
紡ぐことすらできない。
誰かが　不破愛花の死の責任を→
Someone must investigate further
はっきりと　これ以上ない
理由を持って負ってやらねば→
to take responsibility for Fuwa Aika's death,
あの二人は　ダメになるよ。
or those two will be ruined.
Don't you think this whole situation was inevitable,
considering I was the one who brought them into this mess?
その役目を　この事件に
二人を巻き込んだ私が負うのは→
必然と思わんか？
So that's why you'll kill Aika yourself?
だから　葉風ちゃんが
直接　愛花さんを殺害すると？
I'm only saying that if there's a reason to do so, then I will.
（葉風）その必要があれば
迷わず　そうするというだけだ。→
If it isn't necessary, of course I won't.
しないで済むなら　やらんよ。
But I am also a woman.
（葉風）しかし　私も女だ。
（２人）ん？
I may grow angry at Fuwa Aika
and end up killing her in a fit of rage.
単に
本物の不破愛花にむかついて→
発作的に
殺してしまうかもしれんがな。
The motive would be temporary insanity caused by love.
動機は　よくある
痴情のもつれというやつだ。
もはや　是非もないか。
是非もないね。
Apparently it's inevitable.
Yep, inevitable...
（左門）だが　これは　悪意なく→
But are we really headed toward the best conclusion, for the best reasons?
最善の結末に
向かっているのだろうか…。
Okay. This way, this way.
（山本）
はいは～い　こっち　こっち！→
All right, all right!
オーライ　オーライ！
ようやく　すべてがそろったな。
（滝川吉野）葉風さん→
We finally have everything.
Miss Hakaze,
少し　いいですか？
do you have a moment?
潤一郎さんは
ああ言いましたけど→
I know what Junichiro said,
葉風さんが過去に戻る
タイミングがうまく合えば→
but I can't help wondering if you couldn't save Aika in some secret way
愛花ちゃんを助ける
裏技があるんじゃないかって…。
if you went back at just the right time,
considering the fact that you were also
meant to be dead but are currently alive.
死んだと思われた葉風さんも→
こうして　現在に生きて戻る方法が
あったんですから→
ひょっとしたら…。
たまげたヤツだな。→
So maybe...
You are unbelievable.
私のときとは
条件が違いすぎるぞ。
The circumstances are completely different from mine.
That's true, but...
それはそうなんですけど…。
（葉風）そうだな　例えばだ→
I mean,
for example,
if we could find a body of a girl who looked identical to Fuwa Aika
不破愛花そっくりの娘の死体を
用意して→
and we switched it with the real thing,
本物の彼女と　すり替えられれば→
it might be possible to avoid her death.
不破愛花の死は
なかったことにできるかもな。
だがな　吉野。
But, Yoshino,
that would be a rather cruel thing to do,
それは　お前にほれている
私の気持ちを利用して→
手を汚させ
自分の恋人を救わせようという→
using me to get your girlfriend back,
despite knowing that I'm in love with you.
なんとも
あくどい手口ではないか？
あっ　いや　そんなつもりは…。
（葉風）吉野→
That wasn't my inten—
Yoshino.
不破愛花は生き返らん。
Fuwa Aika will not return to life.
No matter how you try to twist the truth,
彼女は
どんな詐術も受け付けんほど→
she is already most certainly dead.
完璧な死を迎えている。→
お前にも　私にも　真広にも
どうにもならんのだ。
There is nothing that you, I, or Mahiro can do.
（葉風）彼女が生きていれば
どんなにいいかと思うが→
I can imagine how wonderful it'd be if she were alive,
but it goes entirely too far against logic.
それは　あまりに
理を　犯しすぎる。→
正直言えば
私は　お前にほれているゆえに→
To be honest,
because of my love for you, I still want to save her,
彼女を助けたいとも思い→
お前にほれているゆえに
彼女を助けられんとも思う。→
but because of the same love for you,
I don't think I can.
だから→
That is why
お前の願いは
とても　むごいのだよ。
your wish is rather unkind.
許せ　吉野。
Please forgive me, Yoshino.
そのかわり私は　お前のために
できるかぎりのことをしよう。
In return, I will do all I can for you.
準備がある。　それではな。
I should get ready now, so I'll see you later.
（葉風）((「せめて
奇跡に等しいものをお目にかけ→
At least bring forth a wonder, to content ye
喜んでいただきたい→
公国を取り戻した私の喜びに
劣らぬはずだ」))
As much as me my dukedom.
((「テンペスト」において
魔法使いプロスペローは→
In The Tempest, Prospero abandons magic
若い者たちの未来を祝福し
魔法を捨てるのだ))
for the sake of the young people's future.
((仮に　私が過去で　不破愛花を
殺すことになっても→
Even if I must kill Fuwa Aika in the past,
それに倣おうと思う))
I mean to learn from it.
((でも　それは
悲劇じゃないのかい？→
But wouldn't that be a tragedy,
好きな人の彼女を殺し
憎まれるというのは))
to kill the girlfriend of the one you love and to be hated by him?
（心の声）≪たとえ憎まれても→
Even if he hates me,
ほれた相手に　一生
忘れられない形で死ねるのなら→
being able to die with the knowledge that the one I love will never forget me...
女として　これ以上の幸福は
ないではないか　潤兄さん≫
There is no greater happiness for a woman, Jun.
Well then, I'll be traveling to the past for a while.
さて　では　少しばかり
過去に行ってこようか。
くれぐれも慎重に動いてください。
下手　打つなよ。
Please be careful.
Don't do anything stupid.
（葉風）
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
始まりにありし　はじまりの樹→
tree that has existed since the beginning, Tree of Genesis,
my name is Kusaribe Hakaze.
我が名は　鎖部葉風。
今ひとたび　我が望みし時間に
この身を移さん！
This once, send me back to the time that I wish!
コン
ガシャン
（山本）
無事に時間の壁を…　越えた？
She made it safely beyond the wall of time?
キィー　キィー　キィー　キィー
It's rather strange to feel nostalgia.
懐かしいというのも
妙な気がするが…。
（葉風）戻ってきたぞ　過去へ！
I have returned to the past!
（左門・通信）
ご無事で何よりです。→
I am pleased to hear you arrived safely.
The next issue is to find out exactly how far into the past you are.
次の問題は　そちらが
どの程度の過去かですが…。
（葉風）
うむ　周囲の変化からすると→
Well, judging by the change in the surroundings and my belongings,
以前　私が現代に戻った時点から
半年以上は過ぎているな。
it's been about half a year since I left.
So around a year and a half from your present.
そちらから見れば
１年半前くらいか。
That's only like a month before Aika was killed!
愛花が殺される
１か月前くらいじゃねぇか！
それで間に合うのかよ？
（葉風・通信）心配するな。→
Will that be enough time?
There's no need to worry.
I've located the offering that Samon left.
左門の残した供物も発見できた。→
It won't take me a month to reach Japan.
日本まで渡るのに
１か月もかからん。
Very well, Princess.
（左門・通信）では姫様
こちらは　樽と骨と人形を→
I shall safeguard the skeleton, the doll, and the barrel in the meantime.
厳重に保管します。
ああ　任せる。→
Yes, I'm counting on you.
（通信）ただし　こちら側の人形は
魔法を　一時解除する。
However, I shall rescind the doll's magic for a while on this end.
（左門）なぜです？
（葉風）パスポートもない私は→
Why?
Since I have no passport,
これから
密入国を繰り返すことになる。→
I'll need to enter the country illegally.
不意に貴様から連絡があれば
周囲に不審がられ目立ちかねん。→
If you contact me at the wrong time,
it will raise suspicion and bring unwanted attention.
それに
もし　不破愛花殺害の犯人が→
Furthermore, if Fuwa Aika's killer is the real mage of Exodus,
本物の
絶園の魔法使いだったとしたら→
there's a possibility that he may be able
通信を感知されるおそれもある。
to sense the communication.
そっ　それでは
こちらで問題が起こったときは!?
Then should some problem arise here—
（葉風・通信）相談されても
過去にいる私には何もできんぞ。
Even if we were to discuss it,
there is nothing I could do from the past.
第一　そちらより　こちらの方が
何が起こるか分からんのだ。
Besides, it's harder to tell what will happen here than over there.
That is a valid point, but...
（左門）それはそうですが…。
Miss Hakaze, I won't ask you to do anything unreasonable now.
葉風さん　今更　無理は言いません。
（通信）ただ無事に
生きて帰って来てください。
Just please return, safe and sound.
≪「無理は言わん」か≫
Nothing unreasonable, huh?
≪そうだな　私は
理のままにしか動けん姫宮だ≫
Well,
I am the Princess of Genesis, bound by the limits of reason.
では　しばらく。
Until later then!
All right, time to go.
さて　出立だな。
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹→
Tree within the tree,
great tree within the great tree,
我が名は　鎖部葉風。
my name is Kusaribe Hakaze.
まずは　ざっと３００キロ→
First things first, time to cross 300 km of ocean.
海を駆けるとしようか。
（左門）真広に滝川吉野。→
Mahiro and Takigawa Yoshino.
今更　言っても手遅れだが→
It's a little late to say this,
お前たちなら
過去に行った姫様が起こす→
but I'm sure you two
are aware of the worst-case scenario with the princess's trip to the past.
最悪のケースに
気付いているだろうな？
Yeah.
ああ。　葉風が　その手で→
The possibility that Hakaze will kill Aika with her own hands.
愛花を殺すかもしれないって
可能性か？
Huh? How would it come to that?
（羽村）えっ!?　どうして
そんなことになるの!?
そういう女心が分かんねぇから→
Maybe you got dumped because you don't understand women.
振られたんじゃねぇのか？
（羽村）うっ…。
で　もし　姫様が犯人となれば
お前は　どうする？
If the princess becomes the murderer, what will you do?
That's obvious.
決まってるよ。
葉風を　この手で殺す。
I'll kill Hakaze myself,
約束どおりだ。
just like I promised.
滝川吉野　お前は？
What about you, Takigawa Yoshino?
理由しだいでは
葉風さんを責めません。
Whatever happens, I won't blame Miss Hakaze,
真広にも殺させません。
and I won't let Mahiro kill her either.
もう　誰かを殺すとか
殺されるとかは　たくさんです。
I've had enough of killing people or people getting killed.
それに　葉風さんが
愛花ちゃんを殺すだなんて→
Besides, it's hard to imagine that Miss Hakaze
そんなことありえませんよ。
would kill Aika.
（山本）一応　もう一つ。
葉風さんが過去で→
One more thing, just in case.
What do you think will happen
吉野君が　不破愛花を殺害するのを
目撃したら→
if Miss Hakaze happens to witness Yoshino killing Fuwa Aika?
どうなると思う？
（羽村）まさか!?
That's impossible!
Even if Yoshino does not think himself to be the mage of Exodus,
たとえ吉野君に　絶園の魔法使い
という自覚がなくても→
別の人格が隠されていたり
その部分の記憶だけ→
he could have a split personality,
and it may be that the other self's memory is suppressed.
封じられていることも
あるんじゃないの？
そのときは→
In that case,
俺が殺す相手が
吉野に変わるだけだよ。
all that changes is that I'd be killing Yoshino.
そうですね　そのときは→
Indeed.
I wonder what would happen then.
どうなるんでしょうね。
（早河）姫君が過去に飛び立ってから
かなりたつが→
It's been some time since the princess went to the past.
連絡は？
（山本）全然。
Any word?
No, nothing.
Well, I suppose we can assume she's fine since she hasn't contacted us.
まっ　便りがないのは
元気なしるしってやつじゃない？
ほかの連中は　どうしている？
How are the others?
Hanemura is training as usual.
（山本）
羽村君は　相変わらず　特訓中。
（羽村）えい！
（潤一郎）うわっ！　うっ！
（山本）ああ　そうそう。　ついに→
Oh, right...
It seems he's finally capable of beating Junichiro.
潤一郎君を打ち負かすことが
できるようになったみたいよ。
Well, that's impressive.
それは　すごいな。
不破真広と滝川吉野は？
What about Fuwa Mahiro and Takigawa Yoshino?
（山本）特にすることもなく
羽村君の特訓につきあったり→
Without much to do,
they've been keeping Hanemura company during his training
買い出しに
出かけたりしてるけど→
as well as shopping,
though I'm sure they're not doing as well as they seem.
内心　穏やかじゃないとは思う。
The object of their revenge depends on the princess's findings, huh?
（早河）姫君の調査の結果しだいで
復讐の相手が決まる…　か。
Actually, we should strike while the cat's away.
（山本）鬼のいぬ間に　打てる手を
打たないといけないんだけどね～。
最近→
Right now,
public opinion seems to be against destroying the Tree of Genesis.
世論では　はじまりの樹の擁護論が
強まっている。
絶園の魔法使いの必要性を
強調したいところなんだがな。
I'd like to emphasize the necessity of us having the mage of Exodus, but...
But even though we've been destroying the Tree,
かといって
あちこちの樹を壊して回っても→
it's had the opposite effect, right?
すでに逆効果って感じでしょう？
ああ。
Yes.
Protect the Tree            Conserve            Keep the Peace!
In the end, people prefer making sacrifices in exchange for benefits,
（山本）人が望むのは
結局　生贄と交換に恵みをくれる→
Protect the Tree    Preserve the Tree for the sake of peace!
just like the Tree of Genesis.
はじまりの樹だったってことね。
だが　俺の立場で　それを
認めるわけにはいかない。
But in my position I can't accept that.
ただな
はじまりの樹が危険と分かって→
Besides,
even if we can establish the Tree of Genesis as a threat and then destroy it,
完全に破壊できたとしても→
あんまり明るい未来は
期待できないんだよ。
it's not like we have the brightest future in store for us.
Why not?
なんで？
（早河）はじまりの樹は→
Regardless of its methods,
the Tree of Genesis brought the world stability.
曲がりなりにも
世界に安定をもたらした。→
Once its restrictions are lifted,
そのおもしがなくなったとき
戦争とか犯罪で→
the ambitions of those who desire to wage wars and commit crimes
利益を得たがっている連中の欲望が
一気に噴き出すだろう。
will run rampant.
However abnormal its ways are, we might think we would've been better off with the Tree ruling us.
不気味でも
樹に支配されていた方が→
どんなによかったか…。→
We may have to endure that kind of chaos for a while.
そんな時代が
しばらく続くかもしれない。
ふっ…　なんにせよ→
Whatever may come to pass,
let's hope nothing happens while the princess is away.
お姫様がいない間は→
異変が起こらないよう
願いたいわね。
I slept quite well thanks to your driving.
（葉風）丁寧な運転で　よく眠れた。
なんとか　たどりついたか。→
So I made it somehow.
I doubt anyone here could imagine that in a year, this whole place will be ruins.
この街も
１年後には廃墟になるとは→
誰も思わんだろうな。
≪不破愛花が
殺されたとされる時間まで→
There are about four and a half hours
残り約４時間半≫
until Fuwa Aika's supposed time of death.
It'll take about thirty minutes to get to the Fuwa mansion.
≪不破の屋敷までは３０分ほど≫
≪この余裕が何をもたらすか…≫
What will happen in that time?
≪どう転んでも
長い夜になりそうだ≫
No matter how it goes, it'll probably be a long night.
（葉風）≪あれは→
That's
不破愛花!?　なぜだ!?≫
Fuwa Aika!
Why?
≪なぜ不破愛花が　こんな所に!?≫
Why is Fuwa Aika in a place like this?
≪あっ…　違う≫
What am I saying?
≪ここは　あの娘の地元だ≫
This is the girl's hometown.
≪むしろ　私が　ここにいる方が
異常事態なのだ≫
My being here is what's unusual.
I hope this is just some coincidence.
（葉風）≪これが
ただの偶然であればよいが…≫
（愛花）私を…。
（葉風）はっ！
You...
（愛花）私を
気にされていたようですが→
You appeared to be staring at me.
どこかで　お会いしたことが？
Have we met?
O-Oh, no...
（葉風）
あっ　いや　会ったことはないが…。
W-We haven't met, but...
Well, your yakitori looked pretty good.
あっ…　その焼き鳥が
うまそうだったからな→
どこで買ったのかと
気になっただけだ。
I was just wondering where you got it.
これは　向こうにある
焼き鳥店で売ってますよ。
This is from the yakitori place over there.
値段も手ごろで　おすすめです。
They're quite cheap, so I highly recommend them.
そうか。　では　私も買うとしよう。
Oh. Then I'll probably get some.
礼を言う。
Thank you.
Tree within the tree,
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹。
great tree within the great tree.
まあ　何も
慌てて逃げることはなかったな。
Well, I guess there wasn't any reason to retreat in such a hurry.
不破愛花は
私も魔法も知らんのだ。
Fuwa Aika doesn't know about me or magic,
but having now seen her in person, I can definitely say she's unique.
しかし　実際に見ると→
独特の雰囲気を持つ娘だったな。
あれで性格が悪いとなれば
確かに扱いづらかろう。
They say her personality was terrible too,
so I'm sure she was a handful.
ふふっ　吉野も
よく彼氏をやっていられたものだ。
It's amazing Yoshino could have handled being her boyfriend.
≪（愛花）吉野さんと私の関係を
知っているなんて妙ですね。→
How strange that you know about Yoshino and me.
それに　魔法とも言ってました。
Moreover, you mentioned magic.
Well, I'm certain it'd be impossible for you to get up here so quickly otherwise.
まあ　そんな力でもなければ→
この屋上に　一瞬で
飛べなかったでしょうけど。
それに　私のことを
性格が悪いと言うのは→
Furthermore, the only ones who would call my personality bad are Mahiro and Yoshino,
吉野さんと真広くらいですが→
真広は　私と吉野さんのことを
知りませんし→
but Mahiro doesn't know about Yoshino and me,
吉野さんが
私のことを話すとも思えません。
and I doubt that Yoshino would talk about me.
Why is this girl so calm?
≪なぜ　この娘は
こんなに冷静なのだ？≫
また　彼氏をやっていられたと→
Also, I can't help but notice you used the past tense, "handled being her boyfriend."
過去形で言ったのも
引っ掛かります。
More importantly, how did she get on the roof?
≪いや　そもそも
どうやって屋上に来られた？≫
なるほど　分かりました。
Oh, I understand now.
あなたは
はじまりの樹の縁者ですね？
You are a representative of the Tree of Genesis, are you not?
And judging by your power and demeanor,
（愛花）そして
その力の程や物腰からすると→
中でも　高い地位にある者では
ありませんか？
you are one of the more powerful amongst them, correct?
I-Indeed, I am the Princess of Genesis,
確かに　私は
はじまりの姫宮ではあるが→
なぜ　そんなことが分かる？
初歩的な推理ですよ。
but how would you know that?
Merely some basic deductive reasoning.
Basic deductive reasoning wouldn't lead anyone to the Tree of Genesis.
推理で　はじまりの樹などという
言葉が出てくるか！
真面目ですね。
You're so serious.
I only wanted to act the part of a master detective.
名探偵を
気取ってみただけじゃないですか。
It appears something irregular is happening.
イレギュラーなことが
起こっているようですね。
本来なら　こういう形で
名乗るべきではないのですが→
Usually, I wouldn't introduce myself this way,
but the situation seems convenient for me too.
私にとって　都合のいい展開なのも
事実でしょう。
はじめまして　私は不破愛花。
A pleasure to meet you. My name is Fuwa Aika,
そして　あなた方が→
and I am the one who carries the will of what you call the Tree of Exodus,
絶園の樹と呼ぶものの
意を受ける者→
その力と真実を担う者。
the one who bears its power and truth.
さしずめ　あなた方なら→
Or simply put, I am the one
絶園の魔法使いとでも
呼ぶ者でしょうか。
you people probably call the mage of Exodus.
不破愛花…。
Fuwa Aika...
（葉風）お前が本物の→
You're really
the actual mage of Exodus?
完全なる
絶園の魔法使いというのか!?
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
What is that?
Some of what
you've been saying is quite incomprehensible.
According to the theory,
it would be the final test.
If I'd known, I wouldn't have had to
suffer through studying for entrance exams.
（船長）Ｗｈａｔ’ｓ？　Ｗｈａｔ　ｉｓ　ｔｈａｔ!?
And what if we fail the test?
I'm not going to think about the consequences...
（愛花）
先ほどから　あなたの言葉には→
I couldn't tell if they were slow
or simply had a screw loose.
不可解なところがあります。
I guess...
Episode 21
Femme Fatale (Woman of Fate)